President Thomas Ehrlich speeches, 1987-1994 C64
Indiana University Archives
President Thomas Ehrlich speeches
1987-1994
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University. President
C64
3.4 cubic feet 4 boxes
Collection consists of speeches given by Thomas Ehrlich during his tenure as president of Indiana University, 1987-1994.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.
Biographical Note
Thomas Ehrlich was born on March 4, 1934 in Cambridge, Massachusetts. He became president of Indiana University on August 1, 1987. During his presidency he concentrated on an academic agenda to enhance IU's position as an international research university of the first rank, and simultaneously a national leader in reaching out to higher education's emerging new majority of nontraditional students. Ehrlich is a scholar, educator, university administrator, lawyer, and governmental executive. He was Provost (chief academic officer responsible for all educational research components of the university and all aspects of student affairs) and Professor of Law at the University of Pennsylvania before serving as President at Indiana.
In the 1970s Ehrlich was Dean and Richard E. Lang Professor at the Stanford University Law School; first President of Legal Services Corporation in Washington D.C.; and first Director of the International Development Cooperation Agency, also in Washington D.C. After graduating from law school, President Ehrlich served as a law clerk for highly respected Judge Learned Hand of the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit in New York City.
Ehrlich became chair of the Midwest Universities Consortium for International Activities' Big Ten Council of Presidents on July 1, and served on the boards of several national organizations. He has undertaken a number of special responsibilities for the United States government. In 1991 he was appointed by President Bush to the Board of Directors of the Commission on National and Community Service. He was reappointed in 1992 and served as Chairman of the Board. He also served as the executive-committee chair of Campus Compact, an organization of college and university presidents, formed to promote student volunteer service.
He was graduated magna cum laude from both Harvard College (A.B. 1956) and Harvard Law School (LL.B. 1959). He was elected to Phi Beta Kappa and served as Article Editor for the Harvard Law Review. He has three honorary degrees, from Notre Dame (1980), Villanova University (1979), and the University of Pennsylvania (1987), and is author or co-author of several books and many articles.
In addition to his presidential duties at Indiana University, President Ehrlich served as professor of law and regularly taught undergraduates and law students. His tenure as president ended following the 1994 school year. After retiring from IU, he spent a semester teaching at Duke University before moving to California. He then moved to California where he became a Distinguished University Scholar at California State University and an adjunct professor at Stanford Law School. President Ehrlich and his wife, Ellen Rome Ehrlich, have three children, David, Elizabeth, and Paul. *Biography excerpted from 1993 Biographical Sketch with minor revisions.
Arrangement
Speeches of President Thomas Ehrlich arranged chronologically.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of speeches given by Thomas Ehrlich during his tenure as the President of Indiana University, dating August 1987 to June 1994.
Acquisition Information
Accessions 1095, 1092, 0408
College presidents --Indiana --Archives.; College orations --Indiana University.; Indiana University -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Indiana University. President -- Archives; Ehrlich, Thomas, 1934- -- Archives
- Speeches, 1987-1994
  - Law School Commencement, May 1987 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Luncheon, 2 Aug 1987 (Box 1)
  - National Junior Achievement Conference, 9 Aug 1987 (Box 1)
  - Freshman Induction Ceremony, 26 Aug 1987 (Box 1)
  - Law Conference Dinner, 11 Sep 1987 (Box 1)
  - The Inauguration of Thomas Ehrlich and Academic Convocation, Indianapolis, 11 Oct 1987 (Box 1)
  - Inauguration and Investiture Ceremony with Ehrlich address, "Education and Values" at IU Auditorium, 12 Oct 1987 (Box 1)
  - Chamber of Commerce Luncheon, 21 Oct 1987 (Box 1)
  - Presentation to the State Budget Committee, 23 Oct 1987 (Box 1)
  - Naming the Alice McDonald Nelson Halls of Residence Administration Building, 24 Oct 1987 (Box 1)
  - School of Business Dean's Advisory Council Dinner, 19 Nov 1987 (Box 1)
  - Bloomington & Indianapolis Development Councils, 20 Nov 1987 (Box 1)
  - Opening of the Center on Philanthropy, 23 Nov 1987 (Box 1)
  - Presentation to State Legislators & Guests, 1 Dec 1987 (Box 1)
  - Indiana Chamber of Commerce, 2 Dec 1987 (Box 1)
  - Presentation to the House & Senate Education Committee, 5 Jan 1988 (Box 1)
  - Bloomington Faculty Council, 19 Jan 1988 (Box 1)
  - Black History Month, IMU Frangipani Room, 1 February 1988 (Box 1)
  - Varsity Club Academic Award Winners, 5 Mar 1988 (Box 1)
  - Law Conference Reception, 9 Mar 1988 (Box 1)
  - Presentation to Commission, 10 Mar 1988 (Box 1)
  - LCCD Speech, 25 Mar 1988 (Box 1)
  - Red Carpet Day, 27 Mar 1988 (Box 1)
  - First Office for Women's Affairs Faculty Award, 30 Mar 1988 (Box 1)
  - Founders Day remarks, 20 Apr 1988 (Box 1)
  - Senior Women's Athletes Banquet, 25 Apr 1988 (Box 1)
  - Baccalaureate, 6 May 1988 (Box 1)
  - IUB Commencement, 7 May 1988 (Box 1)
  - IU Southeast Commencement, 9 May 1988 (Box 1)
  - IU South Bend Commencement, 10 May 1988 (Box 1)
  - IU Kokomo Commencement, 10 May 1988 (Box 1)
  - IUPU Fort Wayne Commencement, 11 May 1988 (Box 1)
  - IU Northwest Commencement, 12 May 1988 (Box 1)
  - IU East Commencement, 13 May 1988 (Box 1)
  - IUPUI Commencement, 15 May 1988 (Box 1)
  - Dedication Ceremony of the Electron-Cooled Storage Ring & Building Addition, 2 Jun 1988 (Box 1)
  - Naming of Franklin Hall, 6 Jun 1988 (Box 1)
  - DASA Luncheon, 12 Jun 1988 (Box 1)
  - Freshman Induction Ceremony, 24 Aug 1988 (Box 1)
  - Awarding the University Gold Medal to Wilfred & Mary Bain, 10 Sep 1988 (Box 1)
  - Unveiling of the Ryan Portrait, 16 Sep 1988 (Box 1)
  - Presentation of the Benton Mural Medallions to the Jacobs, 8 Oct 1988 (Box 1)
  - Chemistry Addition Dedication Ceremony, 21 Oct 1988 (Box 1)
  - Science, Engineering and Technology Building Groundbreaking Ceremony, 2 November 1988 (Box 1)
  - Founders Day, 19 Apr 1989 (Box 1)
  - Dedication Ceremony of Indiana Totem, 27 Apr 1989 (Box 1)
  - IUB Commencement, 6 May 1989 (Box 1)
  - IU Southeast Commencement, 8 May 1989 (Box 1)
  - IU South Bend Commencement, 9 May 1989 (Box 1)
  - IU Kokomo Commencement, 9 May 1989 (Box 1)
  - IUPU Fort Wayne Commencement, 10 May 1989 (Box 1)
  - IU Northwest Commencement, 11 May 1989 (Box 1)
  - IU East Commencement, 12 May 1989 (Box 2)
  - IUPUI Commencement, 14 May 1989 (Box 2)
  - Medical Research & Library Building Dedication, 20 May 1989 (Box 2)
  - Groundbreaking Ceremony, Classroom & Laboratory Building, 14 Jun 1989 (Box 2)
  - Groundbreaking for the Center for Excellence in Education, 15 Jun 1989 (Box 2)
  - Campaign Victory Dinner, 17 Jun 1989 (Box 2)
  - DASA Luncheon, 18 Jun 1989 (Box 2)
  - Franklin D. Schurz Library Dedication Ceremony, 23 Jun 1989 (Box 2)
  - Freshman Induction Ceremony, 23 Aug 1989 (Box 2)
  - Indiana State Budget Committee, 31 Aug 1989 (Box 2)
  - Merrill Hall Naming Ceremony, 2 Oct 1989 (Box 2)
  - IUPUI Urban University Symposium, 8 Nov 1989 (Box 2)
  - 1989 E. Ross Bartley Award, 13 Nov 1989 (Box 2)
  - Dedication of the Virgil T. DeVault Gallery, William Hammond Mathers Museum, 27 Nov 1989 (Box 2)
  - Dedication Ceremony, Kelly Student Center and Lab, 4 Dec 1989 (Box 2)
  - Raymond & Laura Weilgus Gallery, 4 Apr 1990 (Box 2)
  - Founders Day Program, 8 Apr 1990 (Box 2)
  - Naming Ceremony of Henry Radford Hope School of Fine Arts, 28 Apr 1990 (Box 2)
  - Baccaulareate, IU Auditorium, 5 PM, 4 May 1990 (Box 2)
  - Commencement Dinner, 4 May 1990 (Box 2)
  - ROTC Commissioning, 4 May 1990 (Box 2)
  - IUB Commencement, 5 May 1990 (Box 2)
  - IU Southeast Commencement, 7 May 1990 (Box 2)
  - IU Kokomo Commencement, 8 May 1990 (Box 2)
  - IU South Bend Commencement, 8 May 1990 (Box 2)
  - IUPU Fort Wayne Commencement, 9 May 1990 (Box 2)
  - IU Northwest Commencement, 10 May 1990 (Box 2)
  - IU East Commencement, 11 May 1990 (Box 2)
  - IUPUI Commencement, 13 May 1990 (Box 2)
  - Dedication Ceremony, H.B Wells Center for Pediatric Research, Riley Hospital, 19 May 1990 (Box 2)
  - DASA Luncheon, 17 Jun 1990 (Box 2)
  - IUPUI University Library, Groundbreaking Ceremony, 1 Aug 1990 (Box 2)
  - IU East Library & Classroom Groundbreaking, 8 Aug 1990 (Box 2)
  - Freshman Induction Ceremony, IU Auditorium, 22 Aug 1990 (Box 2)
  - Presentation to the HEC, 13 Sep 1990 (Box 2)
  - Harry G. Day Lecture Hall Naming Ceremony, 19 Oct 1990 (Box 2)
  - IUSE Groundbreaking Ceremony of Classroom & Office Building, 24 Oct 1990 (Box 2)
  - Dow Chemical Co. Foundation Gift at Chem. Building, 26 Oct 1990 (Box 2)
  - Indiana Center on Global Change and World Peace Opening Ceremony, 29 October 1990 (Box 2)
  - E. Ross Barley Award, IMU University Club, 1 Nov 1990 (Box 2)
  - Dottie Collins, President's Medal for Excellence, 27 Nov 1990 (Box 2)
  - IUPUI Science, Engineering, & Technology Groundbreaking, 8 Feb 1991 (Box 2)
  - U.S. Senate Subcommittee on Education, Arts and Humanities, 21 February 1991 (Box 2)
  - Auditorium 50th Birthday, 23 Mar 1991 (Box 2)
  - Founders Day, 14 Apr 1991 (Box 2)
  - IUB Commencement (10am), 4 May 1991 (Box 2)
  - IUB Commencement (10am & 3:30pm), 4 May 1991 (Box 2)
  - IU Southeast Commencement, 6 May 1991 (Box 2)
  - IU Kokomo Commencement, 7 May 1991 (Box 2)
  - IU South Bend Commencement, 7 May 1991 (Box 3)
  - IU Northwest Commencement, 8 May 1991 (Box 3)
  - IU East Commencement, 10 May 1991 (Box 3)
  - IUPUI Commencement, 12 May 1991 (Box 3)
  - IUPU Fort Wayne Commencement, 13 May 1991 (Box 3)
  - DASA Luncheon, 16 Jun 1991 (Box 3)
  - Karl Flemke, President's Medal, 14 Aug 1991 (Box 3)
  - Freshman Induction Ceremony, 25 Aug 1991 (Box 3)
  - Minority Attainment Conference, 17 September 1991 (Box 3)
  - Carmel Clay Chamber of Commerce Luncheon, 9 Oct 1991 (Box 3)
  - Student Building Rededication, 11 Oct 1991 (Box 3)
  - Installation of Emita B. Hill as Chancellor of Kokomo Campus, 27 Oct 1991 (Box 3)
  - Cyclotron Facility Groundbreaking, 26 Nov 1991 (Box 3)
  - December Graduates Reception, 9 Dec 1991 (Box 3)
  - Dowling International Center, 14 Feb 1992 (Box 3)
  - Founders Day, 12 Apr 1992 (Box 3)
  - Lindley Hall Rededication Ceremony, 24 Apr 1992 (Box 3)
  - ROTC Commissioning Ceremony, 8 May 1992 (Box 3)
  - IUB Commencement, 9 May 1992 (Box 3)
  - IUPUI Commencement, 10 May 1992 (Box 3)
  - IU Southeast Commencement, 11 May 1992 (Box 3)
  - IU Kokomo Commencement, 12 May 1992 (Box 3)
  - IU South Bend Commencement, 12 May 1992 (Box 3)
  - IUPU Fort Wayne Commencement, 13 May 1992 (Box 3)
  - IU Northwest Commencement, 14 May 1992 (Box 3)
  - IU East Commencement, 15 May 1992 (Box 3)
  - DASA Luncheon, 7 Jun 1992 (Box 3)
  - Brice E. Hayes Hall Dedication, 12 Jun 1992 (Box 3)
  - Freshman Induction, 26 Aug 1992 (Box 3)
  - Briefing on the National Accessibility Center, Bradford Woods, 1 Sep 1992 (Box 3)
  - Rotary Club of New Albany, 3 Sep 1992 (Box 3)
  - Knobview Hall Dedication Ceremony, 3 Sep 1992 (Box 3)
  - Indianapolis Downtown Kiwanis, 18 Sep 1992 (Box 3)
  - Comments to UFC, 13 Oct 1992 (Box 3)
  - Institute for Molecular and Cellular Biology, 16 Oct 1992 (Box 3)
  - Groundbreaking of Student Rec. Center, 23 Oct 1992 (Box 3)
  - Kelley House, Kokomo, 5 Nov 1992 (Box 3)
  - December Graduates Reception, 13 Dec 1992 (Box 3)
  - Half-time Script, 2 Feb 1993 (Box 3)
  - Comments to UFC, 9 Feb 1993 (Box 3)
  - House Ways & Means Committee Hearing, 9 Feb 1993 (Box 3)
  - House Ways & Means Committee Hearing, 16 Feb 1993 (Box 3)
  - School of Business Annual Conference Luncheon, 23 Feb 1993 (Box 3)
  - Founders Day, 7 Mar 1993 (Box 3)
  - E. Ross Bartley Award, 22 Mar 1993 (Box 3)
  - Wright Education, 26 Mar 1993 (Box 3)
  - ROTC Ceremony, 7 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - IUB Commencement, 10 AM, 8 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - IUB Commencement, 3 PM, 8 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - IUPUI Commencement, 9 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - IU Southeast Commencement, 10 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - IU South Bend Commencement, 11 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - IU Kokomo Commencement, 11 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - IUPU Fort Wayne Commencement, 12 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - IU Northwest Commencement, 13 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - IU Northwest, Marram Hall Dedication, 13 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - IU East Commencement, 14 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - Chem. Lab, 26 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - IU Kokomo Library, 27 May 1993 (Box 3)
  - Business-Higher Education Forum, 12 Jun 1993 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Executive Council, 19 Jun 1993 (Box 3)
  - DASA Luncheon, 20 Jun 1993 (Box 3)
  - Freshman Induction, 25 Aug 1993 (Box 3)
  - Mikesell Plaza Dedication Ceremony, IUE, 27 Aug 1993 (Box 3)
  - Paul W. Ogle Cultural & Community Center Groundbreaking Ceremony, IUSE, 14 Oct 1993 (Box 3)
  - Science Buildings Dedication Ceremony, IUPUI, 2 Nov 1993 (Box 3)
  - December Graduates Reception, 11 Dec 1993 (Box 3)
  - E. Ross Bartley Award, 4 Mar 1994 (Box 3)
  - Founders Day, 5 Mar 1994 (Box 4)
  - IUPUI Library Dedication Ceremony, 8 Apr 1994 (Box 4)
  - University Faculty Council Comments, 12 Apr 1994 (Box 4)
  - Classroom/Office Building Groundbreaking Ceremony, IU South Bend, 14 Apr 1994 (Box 4)
  - Cyclotron Building Addition Dedication Ceremony, 29 Apr 1994 (Box 4)
  - Baccalaureate, May 1994 (Box 4)
  - ROTC Ceremony, 6 May 1994 (Box 4)
  - IUB Commencement, 10am, 7 May 1994 (Box 4)
  - IUB Commencement, 3:30pm, 7 May 1994 (Box 4)
  - IU Northwest Commencement, 9 May 1994 (Box 4)
  - Installation of Hilda Richards as Chancellor of IU Northwest, 9 May 1994 (Box 4)
  - IU South Bend Commencement, 10 May 1994 (Box 4)
  - IU Kokomo Commencement, 10 May 1994 (Box 4)
  - IUPU Fort Wayne Commencement, 11 May 1994 (Box 4)
  - IU Southeast Commencement, 12 May 1994 (Box 4)
  - IU East Commencement, 13 May 1994 (Box 4)
  - IUPUI Commencement, 15 May 1994 (Box 4)
  - DASA Luncheon, 19 Jun 1994 (Box 4)